<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE sdocml SYSTEM 
        "http://sdocsml.googlecode.com/dtd/1.0a/sdocml.dtd">

<sdocml>
  <head>
    <defines>
      <incdef url="include/base.xml"/> 
    </defines>
  
    <title>\sdocml Documentation</title>
    <authors>
      <author>
        <firstname>Ulf</firstname>
        <lastname>Worsøe</lastname>
      </author>
      <author>
        <firstname>The self-documenting Documentation System</firstname>
      </author>
    </authors>
  </head>
  
  <section>
    <head><title>Introduction</title></head>

    The \sdocml documentation system defines
    <ilist>
      <li>A front-end XML format that allows use of pseudo-TeX macros.</li>
      <li>A back-end format that is pure XML.</li>
      <li>A compiler (written in Python) that translates fromt he front-end format to the back-end format.</li>
      <li>Compilers translating the back-end format into different final formats (TeX, HTML etc.)</li>
    </ilist>
    The front-end format allows definition of pseudo-TeX macros and
    environments and allows mixing of macros and XML tags.

    <section>
      <head><title>Purpose and focus</title></head>

      The purpose is to provide a fully general framework for a documentation
      system fully supporting graphics, mathematical formulas, code snippets,
      internal cross references and external document references.

      The document format is constructed to be resonably verifiable and
      self-explanatory, and macro functionality has been severely limited
      compared to reak TeX macros to make it more fail-safe.

      Initially the focus of the implementation will be to support features
      required to translate Mosek documentation, into HTML i.e.
      <ilist>
        <li>Correct expansion of all macros.</li>
        <li>Correct and well supported math (via PDFLatex and PNG images).</li>
        <li>Code inclusion and code snippets.</li>
        <li>Full support for index, bibliography and cross references.</li>
        <li>Inclusion of graphics: Raster images as PNG and JPEG, vector images as PDF or EPS.</li>
      </ilist>
      More generally, the aim is to provide detailed error messages and exact
      file/line pointers to where things went wrong. The frontend should always
      guarantee that the output is valid \tt{sdocmlx}, and the backend should always
      produce valid output (and, whenever possible, accept any valid \tt{sdocmlx} document as input).
    </section>

    <section>
      <head><title>Brief history</title></head>
      This project was started to replace the documentation system (based on
      PyLaTeX \cite{pylatex} and plasTeX \cite{plastex:09}) we are currently
      using at MOSEK.

      The original idea was to use a format that was easy to edit for humans
      while defining rigid structure for sections, list, tables etc. DocBook
      (\cite{docbook:09}) was considered, but that would have required adding a
      significant number of features which are not (it seems) immediately
      supported by any DocBook tools.

    </section>
  </section> 

  <section>
    <head>
      <defines><incdef url="include/defs.xml"/></defines>
      <title>User's guide</title>
    </head>

    This chapter describes how to use the document format.
    <section>
      <head><title>Document structure</title></head>

      The overall structure of a \sdocml document is
      <pre type="text/xml" url="include/document-structure.xml"/>
      Between \tagref{head} and the first \tagref{section} goes the bread text. No
      text is allowed between or after the \tagref{section}s.
      Additionally, authors, abstract, date etc. can appear in the header.

      Each section may define or redefine a set of macros in the
      \tagref{defines} section of the \tagref{head}. Macros defined in a section
      head can be used in any section in the document sub-tree rooted at the
      section.
        
      <section id="element:section">
        <head><title>The \tag{section} element</title></head>
        The \tagref{section} element is the primary structural element defining the section nesting structure.

        A \tagref{section} element either contains a mandatory \tagref{head}, some text and
        possibly subsections, or it contains a reference to a section contained
        in a separate file. 

        The text part of a section can contain formatted text, lists, tables,
        math etc. See the reference for \tagref{section} for details. Text
        paragraphs are implicit: One or more blank lines start a new paragraph,
        and certain elements like \tagref{pre}, \tagref{ul}, \tagref{table} etc. define
        a single paragraph. 

        Please note that under certain circumstances blank lines may be
        implicitly introduced when using conditionals: When a scope is left out
        this may leave a blank line if one is not careful.
      </section>

      <section id="element:head">
        <head><title>The \tag{head} element</title></head>
        
        The \tagref{head} tag is required at the beginning of every \tagref{section}
        element and at the beginning of the document (in the \tagref{sdocml}
        element). The \tagref{head} tag contains a mandatory \tagref{title}
        element as well as a list of optional tags:
        \begin{tagdeflist}
          \tagitem{title}
          {
            Defines the title for a section. This element may contain most
            simple text elements but not structural elements, references,
            anchors or math. See section \ref{section:simple-text}
          }
          \tagitem{defines}
          {
            This element defines new macros that can be used in the current
            section and all child-sections. Macros may \em{not} be redefined
            within the same \tagref{defines} element, but redefining a macro
            defined in some parent section is allowed.  

            Macros defined in the \tagref{defines} element in the \tagref{head} of the
            \tagref{sdocml} element can be used anywhere in the document.

            Please see section \ref{element:defines} for details.
          }
          \tagitem{abstract}
          {
            A simple text section that can be used as abstract. This means
            that, in theory, each section may have it's own abstract. It is
            entirely up to the backend to use or ignore this.

            Most text elements, structural text elements and 
          }
          \tagitem{authors}
          {
            This is a structured element that allows defining authors either
            for the entire document or for individual sections.

            Please refer to section \ref{element:authors} for details.
          }
          \tagitem{date}
          {
            Date for the document or section.
          }
        \end{tagdeflist}
      </section> 

      <section id="element:authors">
        <head><title>The \tag{authors} element</title></head>
        This element contains the authors information: Address, email, institution etc. 
      </section>

      <section id="element:defines">
        <head><title>The \tag{defines} element</title></head>

        The \tagref{defines} element may contain four different types of elements:

        \begin{tagdeflist}
          \tagitem{dictentry} { Define a new dictionary entry. }
          \tagitem{def}    { Define a new macro or overrice an existing one.  }
          \tagitem{defenv} { Define a new environment or override an existing one.  }
          \tagitem{incdef} { Include an external file with definitions.  }
        \end{tagdeflist}


        <section id="element:def">
          <head><title>The \tag{def} element</title></head>
          The \tagref{def} element is used to define or redefine a macro. A macro name is defined as follows
          <pre>[a-zA-Z][a-zA-Z0-9@]*|["~\'`^\\][a-zA-Z]|[^\\:!]</pre>
          and furthermore, the special macros ``<tt>begin</tt>'' and
          ``<tt>end</tt>'' are reserved and cannot be redefined.
            
          A macro may require a fixed number of arguments (optional arguments
          are not supported). In the body of the macro definition, the first
          argument can be referred to as ``<nx>{{0}}</nx>'', the second as
          ``<nx>{{1}}</nx>'' and so forth.

          Macros have limited functionality: 
          \begin{itemize}
            \item
            { 
              The body of a macro can only
              define \emph{valid XML}, i.e. it is not possible to define only an
              opening tag or only a closing tag.
            }
            \item
            {
              Since the arguments of the macro are processed before they are
              passed to the macro, it is not possible to use a macro to, say,
              force macros to not be expanded in the argments. 
            }
          \end{itemize}

          In math mode a macro may accept subscript and/or superscript arguments, i.e.
          <pre>\sum^{X}_{i=0} x_i</pre>
          will be interpreted as the macro <tt>sum</tt> with superscript
          argument <tt>X</tt> and subscript argument <tt>i=0</tt>. Using the
          definition of <tt><nx>\sum</nx></tt> from <tt>base.xml</tt>, this will be rendered as
          <math>
            \sum^{X}_{i=0} x_i
          </math>

          To indicate
          that the macro accepts superscript and subscript, use
          <tt>superscript-arg="yes"</tt> and <tt>subscript-arg="yes"</tt>.
          To refer to the subscript and superscript arguments inside the can be
          referred to with ``<nx>{{SUBSCRIPT}}</nx>'' and
          ``<nx>{{SUPERSCRIPT}}</nx>''.

          Both subscript and superscript are optional. If a macro allows an
          argument, but it is not given, it simply expands to an empty string. 
        </section>
        
        <section id="element:defenv">
          <head><title>The \tag{defenv} element</title></head>

          The \tagref{defenv} works much like the \tagref{def} element. Valid macro names are defined as follows:
          <pre>[a-zA-Z][a-zA-Z0-9@]*</pre>
          
          As with macros, it may require a fixed number of arguments, and the
          content of the environment is passwd as an additional argument.  In
          the body of the environment definition, the first argument can be
          referred to as ``<nx>{{0}}</nx>'', the second as ``<nx>{{1}}</nx>''
          and so forth, and the content of the environment can be referred to
          as ``<nx>{{BODY}}</nx>''.
 
          An environment is opened using the special ``<nx>\begin</nx>''
          command and closed with the ``<nx>\end</nx>'' command. In the body
        </section>
        
        <section id="element:incdef">
          <head><title>The \tag{incdef} element</title></head>
          The \tagref{incdef} element can be used to include definitions from external files.
        </section>

        <section id="element:dictentry">
          <head>
            <defines>
              <def m="dictentry" n="2"><d>&lt;dictentry key="{{0}}"&gt;{{1}}&lt;/dictentry&gt;</d> </def>
              <def m="entity" n="1"><d>&amp;{{0}};</d></def>
            </defines>
            <title>The \tag{dictentry} element</title>
          </head>

          This entry can be used to create dictionary entries mapping a key
          string to a value string. Dictionary values can <em>only</em> be
          accessed from within \tagref{def} and \tagref{defenv} elements using the
          \tagref{lookup} element, not fom the content of a section directly.

          One of of the possible uses this was created for was as a way to
          store generated information. For example:
          \begin{itemize}
            \item 
            {
              When include source code snippets, some external program can
              preprocess the code to be included, extract the relevant line
              numbers and store them in the dictionary.
            }
            \item
            {
              Information like version numbers, directories etc.
            }
            \item
            {
              Some tricky accent definitions: Suppose we would like to define
              something like an accenting macro ``<tt><nx>\c</nx></tt>'', such
              that, say
              <pre>
\c{c}   -> &ccedil;
\c{s}   -> &#x15f;
              </pre>
              This cannot be done using macros alone, so instead one might define dictionary mappings 
              <pre macroexpand="yes">
\dictentry{accent-cedilla-c}{\entity{ccedil}}
\dictentry{accent-cedilla-s}{\entity{#x15f}}
              </pre>
              and define the ``<tt><nx>\c</nx></tt>'' macro as follows
              <pre>
&lt;def m="c" n="1"&gt;&lt;lookup&gt;accent-cedilla-{{0}}&lt;/lookup&gt;&lt;/def&gt;
              </pre>
            }
          \end{itemize}
          The scope of a dictionary entry is the document sub-tree rooted at
          the section in which it is defined.
        </section>
      </section>
      <section id="chapter:bread-text">
        <head><title>Document text</title></head>
        <section id="section:simple-text">
          <head><title>Simple text elements</title></head>
          The inline text elements available are
          \begin{tagdeflist}
            \tagitem{bf}{Bold face text.}
            \tagitem{em}{Emphasize text.}
            \tagitem{tt}{Typed text.}
            \tagitem{sc}{Small caps text.}
            \tagitem{br}{Line break.}
            \tagitem{font}{Change font face.}
            \tagitem{img}{Image from external source.}
            \tagitem{nx}{No-expand region. Macros are not expanded within this tag.}
            \tagitem{span}{Generic span element. Works mostly like HTML span.}
          \end{tagdeflist}

          Paragraphs are implicit; as in TeX, one or more blank lines signify a paragraph, but since we are in XML, there are a few extra notes:
          \begin{itemize}
            \item { Blank lines appearing at the beginning and end of an element do not create paragraphs. }
            \item { Blank lines appearing immediately before or immediately after an element which itself generates a paragraph (\tagref{div}, \tagref{center} etc.) do not generate a paragraph. }
            \item { Paragraphs are not generated inside inline-text elements (\tagref{span}, \tagref{tt}, \tagref{bf} etc.) }
            \item { Paragraphs are not generated in preformatted elements. }
          \end{itemize}
          A generated paragraph will never contain a generated paragraph.
        </section>
        <section id="section:structural-text">
          <head><title>Structural text elements</title></head>
          The structural text elements are
          \begin{tagdeflist}
            \tagitem{ilist}
            { Unordered list (e.g. bullet list.) }
            \tagitem{dlist}
            { Definition list. }
            \tagitem{table}
            { Table of values }
            \tagitem{float}
            { A floating element; a figure, a table etc. }
            \tagitem{div}
            { A logical division (works like a HTML div tag). Creates a new text paragraph. }
            \tagitem{center}
            { Centered paragraph. }
            \tagitem{flushleft}
            { Left aligned paragraph. }
            \tagitem{flushright}
            { Right aligned paragraph. }
            \tagitem{pre}
            { 
              Preformatted paragraph. By default  
              \begin{itemize}
                \item{it is typeset with a fixed-size font,}
                \item{all whitespace and all line breaks are kept,}
                \item{macro expansion is not performed}
              \end{itemize}
              Furthermore, it is possible to include external text files (which
              are escaped as necessary --- \emph{not} parsed as XML) or
              snippets from external text files. 

              This element is meant to be used for presenting source code and ASCII art.
            }
          \end{tagdeflist}
        </section>
        <section id="section:math-elements">
          <head><title>Math elements</title></head>
          Math elements are created to reflect TeX math to a wide extend, and
          is slighly inspired by MathML (but it is \emph{not} MathML!).

          There are three different top-level math environments:
          \begin{tagdeflist}
            \tagitem{m}{Inline math element.}
            \tagitem{math}{A math paragraph. This can define an ID making it possible to refer to the equation. }
            \tagitem{eqnarray}{A table of equations. Each equation if a three-cell row with cells aligned as right, center and left respectively. Each row can  define an ID.}
          \end{tagdeflist}
        </section>
        <section id="section:macro-expansion">
          <head><title>Macro expansion</title></head>
          Macros and environments are processed and expanded in most Text and
          Math contexts. A few exceptions are
          \begin{itemize}
            \item { Inside a \tagref{nx} (``No-eXpand'') element. }
            \item { Inside a \tagref{pre} element, unless the <tt>macroexpand="yes"</tt> attribute was given. }
          \end{itemize}
          In all other contexts macros and XML text/math elements may be mixed,
          i.e. arguments for a macro may contain XML tags. Please note that a
          macro-group ``\tt{<nx>{ ... }</nx>}'' can only contain balanced XML
          --- not unmatched opening or closing tags.

          Though the macros look similar to TeX macros, don't let that fool you: It is not TeX. In particular,
          \begin{itemize}
            \item{ Whitespace and linebreaks between a macro and its arguments is ignored. }
            \item{ Macro arguments \emph{must} be a \tt{<nx>{ ... }</nx>} group. }
            \item{ A macro that takes no arguments does \emph{not} consume the succeeding whitespace. }
          \end{itemize}

          <section>
            <head><title>How macros are processed</title></head>
            Macros are not always expanded exactly in the order they appear,
            especially if macros and tags are mixed. The \tt{<nx>{ ... }</nx>}
            construction is denoted a \emph{group}, and basically processing of
            XML elements appearing inside a group is delayed until the group is
            either applied in a macro or ended without being passed as an
            argument to a macro.
    
            The rules are more or less this:
            \begin{itemize}
              \item{ A macro not appearing inside a group and taking no arguments is immediately expanded.} 
              \item{ A macro not appearing inside a group and taking one or more arguments is expanded when all arguments have been supplied. }
              \item{ A macro appearing inside a group is parsed but not expanded until the group is expanded. }
              \item{ An XML element appering inside a group is not processed until the group is either applied in a macro or ends without being passwd to a macro. }
              \item{ Text inside an XML element appearing inside a group is not processed until the XML element is processed. }
            \end{itemize}
            Where \emph{processed} means that the text is parsed or XML
            elements are added to the document structure, and \emph{expanded}
            means that macros are converted their XML definition.

            The parsing and expansion process can be explained in terms of SAX
            events. We are dealing with two kinds of events:
            \begin{itemize}
              \item{Real SAX event. This occurs when the SAX parser encounters an XML tag.}
              \item{Virtual SAX event. This occurs when the expansion of a macro produces an XML tag.}
            \end{itemize}
            If a real event occurs inside a group it is delayed (i.e. it does
            not immediately contribute to the document structure); if an
            element is delayed, all child elements are automatically delayed
            and no text processing performed.

            When the group is expanded, all delayed elements that are immediate
            `children' of the group become virtual events, and their content
            is processed.
            
            Notice that the same group may be expanded several times within a
            macro if the macro applied the same argument several times.

            For example, consider a piece of text of the form
            <pre>
&lt;tt&gt; \aaa { &lt;bf&gt; \bbb  &lt;/bf&gt; } &lt;/tt&gt;
            </pre>
            In this case the following events would take place:
            \begin{enumerate}
              \item{A \tag{tt} SAX event occurs. Since it is not inside a group, it is immediately added to the document structure. }
              \item{The text immediately inside \tag{tt} is processed. A macro <tt>aaa</tt> is encountered. Since it is not inside a group and takes no arguments it is immediately expanded. }
              \item{A group-start is encountered, opening a macro scope. }
              \item{A \tag{bf} SAX event occurs, but since it appears inside a group, it is delayed. }
              \item{Text inside the \tag{bf} element is not processed since \tag{bf} was delayed. }
              \item{A \endtag{bf} SAX event occurs. This closes the \tag{bf} element but otherwise does nothing. }
              \item
              { This text is immediately inside \tag{tt} and is processed. A
                group-end is encountered closing the macro scope. The content
                of the scope, i.e. the delayed SAX events, is processed:
                \begin{itemize}
                  \item
                  { A virtual \tag{bf} SAX event occurs, and since the
                    element appears immediately inside the group being processed,
                    it is added to the document structure. }
                  \item
                  { Since \tag{bf} was not delayed, the text inside the
                    \tag{bf} element is processed: A macro <tt>bbb</tt> is encountered and immediately expanded. }
                  \item
                  { A \endtag{bf} is encountered, closing the \tag{bf} element.
                  }
                \end{itemize}
              }
              \item{A \endtag{tt} is encountered, closing the \tag{tt} element.}
            \end{enumerate}
            We notice that processing is performed in ``layers'': Had yet
            another group containing yet another element appeared inside the
            \tag{bf} element, this would have been delayed in the second stage,
            until a ``<tt><nx>}</nx></tt>'' had been encountered, at which
            point the content of that scope would be processed.

            There are a few special cases to observe:
            \begin{itemize}
              \item
              { A small set of special constructions are converted, specificly
                double left-quotes, double right-quotes, two dashes and three dashes. }
              \item
              { Special table syntax using the constructions
                \begin{description}
                  \ditem{<tt><nx>\:</nx></tt>}
                  { For the first row in a table this produces two virtual SAX events: a
                    start-row and a start-cell. Otherwise it will produce four virtual SAX
                    events: an end-cell, an end-row, a start-row and a start-cell.
                  }
                  \ditem{<tt><nx>\!</nx></tt>}
                  {
                    This evaluates to a two virtual SAX events: an end-cell and a start-cell
                  }
                  \ditem{end-of-table}
                  {
                    Finally, at the end of table, two virtual events are generated: An end-cell and an end-row. 
                  }
                \end{description}
              }
              \item
              {
                The <tt><nx>\begin ... \end</nx></tt> constructions, which work
                almost as macros: the <tt><nx>\begin</nx></tt> opens a group
                and <tt><nx>\end</nx></tt> ends a group.
              }
              \item
              { Superscript and subscript notation in math mode. These are parsed
                \begin{description}
                  \ditem{ <tt><nx>_{ ... }</nx></tt> and <tt><nx>^{ ... }</nx></tt> }
                  {
                    Subscript and superscript where the right-hand operand is a group.
                  }
                  \ditem{ <tt><nx>_.</nx></tt> and <tt><nx>^.</nx></tt> }
                  {
                    Subscript and superscript where the right-hand operand is a single char, e.g. <nx><tt>x^i</tt></nx>
                  }
                \end{description}
                The right-hand operand can \em{not} be a macro.
               
                The left-hand operand must be present (i.e. it may not be
                immediately preceeded by XML markup) and it may be a character,
                a macro, a group or another inorder group.
                \begin{itemize}
                  \item{ If the preceeding item is a macro that accepts subscript or superscript, the right-hand operand is passed to it.}
                  \item{ If the preceeding item is a group or a macro that does not accept the optional argument, it will be used as left-hand operand. }
                  \item{ If the preceeding item is a character, the left-hand operand will be a group consisting of that character. }
                \end{itemize}
                
                Notice that both subscript and superscript is allowed for the
                same left-hand operand, i.e. in ``<nx>x_i^k</nx>'', <tt>i</tt>
                is passed as subscript argument to <tt>x</tt> and <tt>k</tt> is
                passed as superscript argument to <tt>x</tt>. 
                On the other hand, if the left-hand operand is a macro, say
                <nx><tt>\mymacro</tt></nx>, that accepts only subscript, then
                <pre>
\mymacro_x^y
                </pre>
                is interpreted as
                <pre>
{\mymacro_x}^y
                </pre>
                while
                <pre>
\mymacro^y_x
                </pre>
                is interpreted as
                <pre>
{\mymacro}^y_x
                </pre>
                i.e. neither <tt>x</tt> or <tt>y</tt> are passed to the macro. 

                A noticable difference from TeX arises here. Suppose <tt><nx>\mymacro</nx></tt> takes one argument and subscript; then 
                <pre>
\mymacro{QWE}_x
                </pre>
                is equivalent to
                <pre>
\mymacro_x{QWE}
                </pre>
                Furthermore, notice that primes must be used with care, e.g.
                ``<tt><nx>x'_i</nx></tt>'' is interpreted as
                ``<tt><nx>{x'}_i</nx></tt>'' which may not give the expected
                result.
              }
            \end{itemize}
          </section>
        </section>
      </section>
      <section>
        <head><title>The \tag{bibliography} element</title></head>
        The \tagref{bibliography} element defines the special top-level
        bibliography section. The content of the section is either explicitly
        written as a list of \tagref{bibitem} elements or generated from an
        external bibliography database defined by the <tt>url</tt> attribute if \tagref{bibliography}.

        Bibliography items can be linked to by using the \tagref{ref} element with
        the attribute <tt>type="cite"</tt>. Bibliography references are resolved as follows:
        <ilist>
          <li> 
            If the \tagref{bibliography} section contains an explicitly defined
            \tagref{bibitem} with the relevant key, this will be used as target
            for the reference,
          </li>
          <li> 
            otherwise, the relevant item is located in the external bibliography
            database, and a suitable \tagref{bibitem} will be generated from the
            external info.
          </li>
        </ilist>
        The explicitly written \tagref{bibitem}s are simple formatted text
        entries, while the external bibliography database file is defined  in
        BibTeXML format (see \cite{bibtexml:07}) --- e.g. the file used for
        this manual looks like this:
        <pre type="text/xml" url="bibdb.xml"/>
        
        <section>
          <head><title>Bibliography entry formatting</title></head>
          Currently the bibliography entry formatting is hardcoded into
          <tt>sdoc2xml.py</tt> (specificly, in the <tt>BibItemNode</tt> class),
          but it is parameterized and will, ultimately, be moved to a
          configuration file of some sort.

          For each bibliography entry type (\tag{book}, \tag{inbook},
          \tag{article} etc.) there is a formatting string describing how the
          entry should be formatted. The string is interpreted as follows:
          
          <dlist>
            <dt><nx><tt>${N1|N2|...}</tt></nx></dt>
            <dd>
              This expand to the content of the first field <tt>N1</tt>,
              <tt>N2</tt> etc. defined in the bibliography entry. At least one
              of the fields must be defined. Formatting is context sensitive,
              so e.g. multiple authors will be expanded to a meaningful list:
              <ilist>
                <li>``John Doe''</li>
                <li>``John Doe and Jane Doe''</li>
                <li>``John Doe, Jane Doe and Gene Generic''</li>
              </ilist>
            </dd>
            <dt><nx><tt>$[COND]{blabla}{yadayada}</tt></nx></dt>
            <dd>
              This is an \emph{if-then-else} expression --- the second brace
              (the else-clause) may be empty or left out completely.
              
              The cond is a logical expression made from field names --- a name
              <tt>N</tt> evaluates to <tt>true</tt> if and only if the database
              entry contains a field <tt>N</tt>.
            </dd>
          </dlist>
          
          For example a <tt>book</tt> entry, where the fields <tt>title</tt>,
          <tt>year</tt> and <tt>publisher</tt> are mandatory, either
          <tt>author</tt> or <tt>editor</tt> must be defined, either
          <tt>volume</tt> and <tt>number</tt> must be defined, and
          <tt>series</tt> and <tt>address</tt>  (and several other fields) are optional.
          <pre>
${author|editor}. ``${title}''$[series]{, \emph{${series}}, 
  $[volume]{vol. ${volume}}{no. ${number}}}, ${year}. 
  ${publisher}$[address]{, ${address}}.
          </pre>
          This string might expand to something like this:
          <pre>
John Doe, Jane Doe and Gene Generic. 
  ``Staying Anonymous'', \emph{Paranoid's handbooks}, vol. 4, 1984. 
  Doe &amp; Doe Publishing, Delusional Street, San Fransisco.
          </pre>

          The condition syntax is as follows: Each logical expression is either logical OR list, ``<tt>N1|N2|...</tt>'', or a logical AND list,``<tt>N1&amp;N2&amp;...</tt>'', where each <tt>N*</tt> is either a field name or a logical sub-expression, ``<tt>(X)</tt>'', where <tt>X</tt> is a logical expression. For example:
          <pre>
author|editor
series&amp;(volume|number)
organization&amp;publisher&amp;address
          </pre>
        </section>
      </section>
    </section>
    <section>
      <head><title>Special elements</title></head>
      There are a set of special tags meant to be used in the documentation
      writing and building process. These are
      \begin{tagdeflist}
        \tagitem{warning}
        {
          Print a warning to the display when a condition is met.
        }
        \tagitem{error}
        {
          Write a message and halt the translation if a condition is met.
        }
        \tagitem{note}
        {
          Produces a ``margin-note'' for proof-readers.
        }
        \tagitem{sdocml:conditional}
        {
          A special preprocessor-like tag: If the given condition is met, the
          content of the element will be parsed as if it had appeared directly
          in the text rather than in a \tagref{sdocml:conditional}. If the
          condition is not met, the content will be completly ignored (i.e.: It
          must still be valid XML, but no validation is performed and all text
          and elements are thrown away.)
        }
      \end{tagdeflist}

      Furthermore, several elements accept a ``<tt>cond</tt>'' attribute
      defining a condition under which the element should be included in the
      document. If a condition element evaluated to <tt>False</tt>, the element
      will be ignored as if it had appeard inside a \tagref{sdocml:conditional}
      element.
    </section>
  </section>
  <section url="../build/output/tagsref.xml" cond="true"/>
  <section url="../build/output/macroref.xml" cond="final"/>

  <bibliography url="bibdb.xml"/>
</sdocml>

